そんなところだな。
That's about it...
偵察終了！
いつもどおり 異常なしだ。
Scouting complete.
Same as usual,
nothing suspicious.
今日も いい天気だな。
It's another nice day.
Granny, hurry! Hurry!
おばあちゃ～ん！
早く 早く！
これこれ！
そんなに急ぐでないよ。
Now, now. Don't be so hasty.
(ウドン)あ～ん！
任務のあとの
この一本のために➡
A stick of this after a mission...
生きてるんだな～。
This is what I live for.
(モエギ)はぁ…。
(コテツ)さぁ
さっさと選んでもらおうか。
C'mon, hurry and pick a card.
う～ん…。
《白眼！》
Byakugan!
H-Hey! No fair!
おいっ！ なんだよ！
ゲームに白眼は反則だろうが！
You can't use Byakugan
in a game!
さてと 定時報告書でも書くかな。
Well, I guess I'll start on
the next report that's due.
あっ！
《コイツ 暁か！》
Is he from...the Akatsuki?!
《わかった！ 火影様に連絡だな》
Right! Must report this
to Lady Hokage!
わぁ～っ!!
What?!
なにっ!?
うっ！
(天道)いよいよだ。
The time has come.
Assault on the Leaf Village!
(シカマル)自来也様が持ち帰った
３つの情報…。
CIPHER DIVISION
Lord Jiraiya sent back three
sources of information...
(シホ)ぶっちゃけ
雨隠れの忍。 ペインの遺体。
Namely, a ninja from
the Hidden Rain...
Pain's corpse...and...
そして この暗号ですね。
this secret message.
情報部のいのいちさんなら
すぐにも雨隠れの忍から➡
Knowing Inoichi in
the Intel Division,
he'll be able to get
some kind of information
out of the Hidden Rain ninja.
なんらかの情報を
引き出してくれるだろう。
(サクラ)ペインの遺体の検死も➡
Master Shizune has put top priority
シズネ先輩が
最優先でやってるところよ。
on the autopsy of Pain's corpse.
こっちも間違いないわ。
She's sure to learn something too.
そして ナルト君からの情報で
解けた この暗号。
And this message we decoded
with help from Naruto...
「ホンモノハ イナイ」ですね。
"The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them."
オレたちは
これから得られる情報の中から➡
We'll have to take all
this information
and figure out the mystery behind
this guy named Pain.
ペインとかって野郎の謎に
迫らなきゃならねえ。
自来也様ですら
やられちまうような連中の➡
The mystery of someone who
could even take down Lord Jiraiya.
謎ってやつをよ…。
HIDDEN LEAF INTEL DIVISION
A genjutsu block...
(いのいち)幻術プロテクトか。
I'm going to take a peek into your mind.
心の中➡
のぞかせてもらうとしよう。
So many genjutsu blocks...
《これほどの幻術プロテクトを…。
どおりで
自白剤が効かないわけだな》
No wonder truth serum
didn't work on him.
(イビキ)どうでした？
How did it go?
ダメだ。 誰かが
頭の中にプロテクトをかけている。
It's no use...
Someone's placed blocks
inside his mind.
これを潜り抜けるのは 難しいな。
It's going to be difficult to
navigate past them.
おそらく ペインとかいうヤツの
術か何かでしょう。
It's probably some jutsu placed
on him by the one named Pain.
気をつけてください
いのいちさん。
Please be careful, Inoichi.
幻術トラップが
仕掛けてあるかもしれません。
There may be genjutsu traps
set in there as well.
Yes, I'm aware of that.
ああ わかってる。
AUTOPSY ROOM 3
SHIZUNE
OYONE
KUMADORI
These black rods, which
were embedded in the corpse...
《シズネ : 遺体に埋め込まれた
この黒い棒は➡
ペインとよばれる者たちの特徴》
Could they be a special feature
of these men known as Pain?
《なぜ彼らは これを
体に埋め込んでいたのか？
Why did they embed this
into the body?
I must learn more about
検死の前に この金属の特性を
知る必要がある》
the properties of this metal
before the autopsy.
CIPHER DIVISION
(シカマル)暗号の 「ホンモノハ イナイ」。
"The-Real-One's-Not-Among-Them."
それなら そのペインとかっていう
６人は幻術で➡
Maybe the six Pains were genjutsu...
A jutsu created by the female
Akatsuki member
もう１人いたっていう
女の暁の 術かもな。
who was also said to be present.
そいつが陰から
物理的攻撃で自来也様を…。
And she's the one who physically
attacked Lord Jiraiya
from the shadows.
No... That's hard to imagine.
いや そうは考えにくいわ。
フカサク様が言うには➡
According to Lord Fukasaku,
自来也様は 実際には➡
Lord Jiraiya died from being
stabbed by real weapons
その６人に 武器で刺されて
亡くなられたそうよ。
wielded by all six of them.
Well, he took down three of them,
まあ そのペインを３人倒したけど➡
but they supposedly
resurrected themselves...
生き返ったっていうし…。
信じがたい幻術のような話だけど。
It does sound like some
unbelievable genjutsu.
暁に 常識は通じねえよ。
Common sense has no meaning
when it comes to the Akatsuki.
不死のヤツらまで いたんだからな。
There have been others
who were immortal.
とにかく
他の情報が出てくるまで➡
In any case, let's keep hypothesizing
all possible scenarios
ある程度のパターンを できるだけ
推測しておきましょう。
until we get reports from the others.
だな。
You're right.
ナルトが修業から
帰ってくるまでに➡
Let's at least be a little closer
to solving Pain's mystery
少しでも ペインの
謎に近づきましょう。
by the time Naruto returns
from his training.
(シマ)どれ。
Well then...
ほんなら新鮮な食材を
調達してくるけんな。
I'm going to procure us
some fresh ingredients.
《また グロい系かな。
いやだなぁ…》
Not more of that gross stuff...
Aw man...
母ちゃん 精のつくやつ 頼んだで。
Ma! Make sure you get
some stamina-building stuff!
仙術チャクラも
練れるようになったし➡
You are able to mold
Sage Jutsu chakra
蛙組手も仙法も
ある程度 マスターした。
and have pretty much mastered
Frog Kumite and Sage Techniques.
ここで 最後に
ひと言 言うことがある。
Now I have one final thing
to say to you.
な… なに なに？
かしこまっちゃってさ。
Wh-What is it?
You're suddenly so serious.
それはな 仙人モードの
リスクについてじゃ。
Well... It's about the risks of
using Sage Mode.
リスク？
Risks?
そうじゃ そのリスクを
ちゃんと把握できてこそ➡
Yes... Once you fully grasp
the risks involved,
仙人モードが最大限に活かされる！
then you can use Sage Mode
to its fullest extent!
う～ん… で そのリスクって？
So, what are the risks?
まずは ナルトちゃんも
わかっとるとは思うが➡
First, as you're probably aware,
仙人モードは そう長く持続せん。
もって ５分じゃ。
you can't maintain
Sage Mode for too long.
Maybe five minutes at most.
それから 仙人モードになるための
自然エネルギーを集めるには➡
Also, to amass the Nature Energy
necessary to enter Sage Mode,
you must follow the principle
of staying still.
動くな が基本じゃ。
それゆえ 戦闘に入ってからは
まず使えん。
Thus, it cannot be used
once you begin battle.
動かんかったら
敵の格好の的じゃけんの。
For when you are still,
you become an easy target
for your enemy.
((イッテ～！))
Ow!
なるほど。
じゃろ？
I see...
Right?
仙人モードになれるのは➡
So the only time you can go
into Sage Mode is
仲間が たくさんおって
己が フリーになれる時だけじゃ。
when you've got plenty
of comrades around you
that can free you up.
どうしても １人の時に
仙人モードにならにゃいけん時は➡
If you are alone,
but must go into Sage Mode,
いったん戦闘から離脱して
自然エネルギーを集めるしかない。
withdraw from the battle momentarily
and gather Nature Energy.
ああっ 使えねえじゃん 仙人モード！
じゃあ 今まで何のために…。
What?! Then Sage Mode is useless!
So what was all this training for?!
そう がっかりするな。
Don't be so disappointed.
そこで そのリスクを補うために
わしがおるんじゃ。
That is why I am here,
to alleviate that risk.
それって どういうこと？
What do you mean?
わしとナルトちゃんが
体を融合すれば➡
If you and I merge our bodies,
it'll be fine!
それで オーケーじゃ。
No!!
ギャア～！
When I say merge,
融合いうても 背中や肩に➡
it simply means to be lightly
attached to your shoulder or back.
軽く くっつく程度の
融合じゃけんの。
な なんだ… でも なんで
融合すれば オーケーなんだってばよ？
Oh, that's all...
But how does merging
make things fine?
簡単に言えば 静と動の
役割分担をするためじゃ。
Simply put, it's to split
the roles of stillness and action.
片方が動いとる時は
片方が止まって➡
When one is moving,
the other stays still and
gathers Nature Energy.
自然エネルギーを取り込む。
自来也ちゃんも わしら夫婦を
両肩に乗っけた状態が➡
In Jiraiya-boy's case,
the final form of his Sage Mode
仙人モード最終形態じゃった。
had Ma and me both
riding his shoulders.
なるほど そういうことか。
I see... I get it now...
ま 心配するな ナルトちゃんよ。
Don't you worry, Naruto-boy!
オッケー！
Okay!
ここで陽動と探索の
二手に分かれる。
From here on,
we'll be splitting into two teams:
diversion and search.
確認をしておく。
I'll go over it again.
Diversion will be made up
of Shurado, Chikushodo, and Gakido.
陽動は修羅道 畜生道 餓鬼道。
探索は天道➡
Search will be Tendo,
Ningendo, and Jigokudo.
人間道 地獄道でいく。
小南 お前は探索側だ。
(小南)わかってるわ。
Konan, you're with the search team.
I know.
(天道)木ノ葉は
里の地中と上空を含め➡
The Hidden Leaf Village...
is surrounded by
a spherical barrier that
球状の結界を張っている。
includes underground
and aerial coverage.
無断で侵入した人間は➡
Which means anyone
who enters without permission
すぐ感知される仕組み
ということね。
is detected immediately.
作戦どおり畜生道を
木ノ葉上空へ投げ込む。
As planned,
we will launch Chikushodo
into the Hidden Leaf's aerial space.
敵に こっちの人数を誤認させて
かく乱する。
We will confuse the enemy
by not giving them an accurate count.
畜生道からの口寄せを待て。
Wait for Chikushodo's summoning.
イタチと鬼鮫は
簡単に入り込んだらしいけど。
I was told Itachi and Kisame
infiltrated easily.
イタチは木ノ葉の暗部だった男だ。
Itachi once belonged to
the Leaf's Anbu Black Ops.
結界を通り抜ける暗号を
知っていた。
He knew the password
to get through the barrier.
オレにはオレのやり方がある。
I have my own way of doing things.
ここより世界に痛みを。
Starting here,
the world shall know pain...
侵入者だ！
An intruder!
目標は１人 西口イのＢ地点。
Single target, west gate, sector I-B
ねぇ 早く早く！
Hurry, hurry!
Yes, I'm coming dear.
AUTOPSY ROOM 3
SHIZUNE
OYONE
KUMADORI
ごっそ～さん。
ごちそうさま。
Thanks for the food!
Yes, thank you!
散！
Disperse!
何だ？
What is that?
ぐわぁっ！
火遁 豪火球の術！
Fire Style: Fire Ball Jutsu!
オレの火遁が効かない！
My Fire Style has no effect!
こうあちこちで…
いったい どうなってる!?
It's all over the place! What's going on?!
侵入者は１人じゃなかったのか？
I thought there was just one intruder!
すぐに白眼で確認します！
I'll confirm with the Byakugan
right away!
結界班だけでは間に合わん！
This is beyond the scope
of just the Barrier Corps!
他の部隊に連絡して
救援を要請しろ！
Contact other troops and
request backup! Hurry!
急げ！
はっ！
Right!
I'll go notify Lady Hokage!
オレは火影様に連絡に行く！
九尾の情報は 持っていないか。
He holds no information
on the Nine-Tails.
うずまきナルトは どこだ？
Where is Naruto Uzumaki?
コイツも知らんか。
He doesn't know either...
AUTOPSY ROOM 3
SHIZUNE
OYONE
KUMADORI
急に チャクラの計器が反応して
黒い棒が加熱したから➡
The chakra meter shot up suddenly
and the black rod began warming up,
so I thought it was strange.
おかしいと思ったんだ。
These are demodulators for
receiving high frequency chakra waves.
これ 高周波チャクラを受ける
復調装置だったんだ。
復調装置…
つまり なんです？
Demodulator?
Which means what?
つまり これは
チャクラの受信機ってこと。
In other words,
they're chakra receivers!
今 まさに受信してる。
And, it's receiving
at this very moment!
受信機？ どういうことです？
Receiver? What do you mean?
つまり
これが受信機ってことは…。
If this is a receiver...
I don't have time to explain.
っと そんな説明してるより
すぐに綱手様に連絡しなきゃ。
I have to notify Lady Tsunade
immediately...
CIPHER DIVISION
な なんだ？
What was that?
これって！
行くぞ！
What's that?
Let's go!
HIDDEN LEAF INTEL DIVISION
見つけた！
Found it!
(イノ)なんなの？ あっ！
What was that?
チョウジ 私は情報部に連絡を。
(チョウジ)うん。
Choji! I'll notify the Intel Division.
Right!
I have to get to Pa!
《ボクは 父ちゃんのところへ》
お父さん 里が！
Father! The village is...
うわぁ～！
なんだ!?
あっ！
Run!
逃げろ！
たみちゃん。
Tami!
しゃんなろ～！
Cha!
大丈夫？
Are you all right?!
U-Uh-huh.
う うん。
ありがとうございます。
Th-Thank you so much!
うっ！
ムカデが倒れている。
あの子がやってくれたようだ。
The centipede is down...
Seems that girl did it.
よかった そんなに傷は
深くないわね。
Thank goodness!
Your wound is not too deep.
ありがとう。
Thank you...
(イルカ)サクラ！
Sakura!
大丈夫か？
イルカ先生。
Are you all right?
Iruka Sensei...
Just what's going on?
いったい
何が起こってるんですか？
わからん …が 何者かが
木ノ葉に攻めてきた。
I don't know.
But someone is attacking
the Leaf Village!
状況は 綱手様に
すでに連絡した。
The situation has been
reported to Lady Tsunade.
すぐにも
警報が発令されるだろう。
The alarm should sound soon.
里に 直接 攻めてくるなんて。
The village is under direct attack?
いったい何者が？
Who would do such a thing?
いくぞ イルカ。
ああ。
Let's go, Iruka!
Right!
サクラは 急いで病院へ行って
ケガ人を見てくれ。
Sakura, hurry to the hospital
and tend to the wounded.
病院には たくさんのケガ人がいる。
はい。
It's full of injured people.
Yes, sir!
《まさか！》
It can't be...
お姉ちゃん。
Miss...
大丈夫 私たちには
火影様がいるでしょ。
It's going to be all right!
We have Lady Hokage
on our side!
うん。
Uh-huh!
結界班より報告。
Barrier Corps reporting!
侵入者は 木ノ葉上空より潜入。
An intruder entered Hidden
Leaf Village through our air space.
結界反応は単騎。
Our sensors picked up
a single target.
ですが 反応直後より
複数の襲撃を確認しました。
But shortly after detection,
several attacks were confirmed.
分析班より報告。
敵戦力 およそ三個大隊。
《綱手 : これほどの戦力を
悟られることなく運用できる敵。
やはり…》
報告 侵入者の目撃情報。
黒衣に朱色の雲模様。
《暁 ついに来たか》
((予言の子は
あの子であってほしいと➡
そう願わずにはおれんのう。
(自来也ちゃんは すべてを
あの子に託したんじゃからな))
非常事態警報を出せ。
それから ナルトを呼び戻せ。
(ナツ)こいつら…。
(ルーシィ)オラシオンセイス!?
(ハッピー)だよねぇ。
(グレイ)随分雰囲気違くねえか？
(エルザ)メンバーも違うようだな。
(ジャックポット)
ヨホホホホ。 ホイ そろった！ 激アツ！
まさしく これぞオラシオンセイス。
いえいえ…。 新生オラシオンセイスと
お見知りおきください。 ませ！
(みんな)新生オラシオンセイス!?